# kinto behr

# data scientist

## PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a data scientist and statistician with expertise in R and a keen interest in process automation, software engineering, and applied statistics. Although I am most comfortable in R, I have varying degrees of experience with a number of other languages from Python and SQL (fluent), through LaTeX, HTML/CSS and JavaScript and Rust (intermediate).

Outside of work, I am an active contributor to the open source software community, having developed or made large contributions to a number of R packages. More information and an expanded resume are available at https://kinto-b.github.io

# **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

#### Statistician

Social Research Centre | 2022 - Present

I am currently shared between the data and statistical methods teams, spending half my time in each. This being the case, I work on a fairly wide variety of things. On the one hand, I am responsible for carrying out various statistical procedures (e.g. weighting, small area estimation, propensity modelling) and writing technical reports. On the other hand, I am the technical lead on a variety of software engineering projects, typically focussed on data modeling, processing, analysis and reporting, but often general application development. Some of the things I've worked on in this latter capacity are:

- Developing a three-tier lottery application for setting up and running prize draws.
- Deploying machine learning models and designing API access to them to retrieve predictions
- Redesigning the SQL database and associated workflows that underpin the Life in Australia study.

# **Data Scientist**

Social Research Centre | 2020 - 2022

I was the lead data scientist on the SES, which approaches hundreds of thousands of higher education students each year. In this capacity, I was responsible for maintaining the data infrustructure throughout the full length of the pipeline from sample collection and validation, through fieldwork operations and data processing, to report production.

In addition, I made key contributions to the in-house R package architecture and Shiny application suite. In particular, I

- Authored and/or maintained the majority of in-house packages
- Trained other data scientists in R package development, helping them to become maintainers in their own right
- Developed a number of complex Shiny applications which became core to projects across the business, including one which won a company-wide competition

#### Team Lead

Sidekicker | 2018 - 2020

I was in charge of the community operations team, which was responsible for ensuring that the application marketplace was running smoothly. Alongside managing 15+ casual staff, I performed data analysis using SQL and Python, and automated core processes to save 100hrs of labour-time per month.

## **EDUCATION**

# **Master of Statistics**

University of New South Wales | 2021-2023

- Graduated with excellence
- Thesis title: Classification using Semi-supervised Learning
- WAM: 92%

## Bachelor of Arts (Honours)

University of Melbourne | 2019

- Recieved the Hastie Prize for graduating top of my class
- Thesis title: Epistemic Relativism: The Futility of the Argument from the Criterion
- GPA: 4.0 (WAM: 87%)

# Bachelor of Arts and Bachelor of Science

Monash University | 2013 - 2017

- Received numerous academic awards including the Peter J. Lloyd prize in Theoretical Physics, the Dean's List Fellowship Award and five best in unit awards for achieving top marks across various physics courses
- Majors (minors): Philosophy (Japanese) and Physics (Mathematics)
- GPA: 3.93 (WAM: 87%)

# **SELECTED HONOURS**

- 2019 Hastie Prize in Philosophy, the University of Melbourne
- 2016 Peter J. Lloyd Prize in Theoretical Physics, Monash University